Hello friends, my name is Jai Sharma and
welcome to our YouTube channel.
Friends, today we are going to talk
about the plan of ICCI Lombard, whose name
is Health Advantage.
Today we will talk about this plan. So,
those who are new to our channel, please subscribe to
our channel so that you can get
notifications of such videos made. So
let's start.
[Music]
So first of all, let's talk
about ICICI Lombard company. Friends,
this Lombard is a collaboration of two companies. In
which the first company is our
ICC Bank, which is an Indian bank. The
percentage share of SSC Bank
is 64% and the second company
is Fairfax Financial Holding Limited,
whose share is 36%, which is a
Canadian based company.
So, together both the companies run the
company ICICI Lombard in India.
These people look after the health insurance. So
friends, let's talk about this plan.
Friends, whenever you take this plan,
in this the company gives you  They offer sums ranging from ₹500000 to ₹
3 crore,
whichever suits you, you can add that much as per your convenience,
minimum ₹5 lakh and
maximum ₹3 crore.
Talking about the entry, if you are an adult,
your entry age will be 18 years. The
minimum age should be 18 years, only
after that you can take this policy
and the maximum age is
65 years. If you are 66 years old, then you
cannot take the policy, hence
any person up to 65 years of age can take this policy if he
wants to take it. Talking about the child, the
minimum entry age for the child is
90 years and the maximum age
for the child is 25 years. If there is a
dependent child, then if the child turns 26, then the
list will automatically be removed,
hence the maximum age
for the child will remain ₹25 only.
Even when new children are added, it is 25. If
children are added, then it is also 25 on 26.  The
company will automatically remove it from there. Let's
talk about the policy term, so you
can buy it for 3 years together. You can take 200 rupees for one year or
3 years, whichever term suits you.
If you
take more than one term, you
get discount offers. If you are taking it for two years, then the
company offers you a discount of 7.30%. If you are
taking the policy for three years, then the
company gives you a discount of 12.5%. Let's
talk about the free look period,
friends, if you do not understand any terms and conditions
of this policy or if
an agent or someone else gave you wrong
information about it, you come to
know about it later, then you
can also take a free look at this policy. The
company will refund your entire money within 15 days
if you take a free look at it.
In case you have time, then the company
refunds your entire money there. Let's
talk about cancellation, you
can also cancel this policy.  It is not
that you cannot cancel it even after your period is over.
You can cancel it even then.
If you cancel the policy within 3 months, the
company
refunds you 75% of your money. If you cancel it between three to
six months, then we will
refund you 50% of your money. If you
cancel it between 6 to 9 months, then the
company will refund 25% of your premium. If
you cancel it between nine to 12 months, then the
company will not refund you anything.
Talking about renewal, you
can renew it for lifetime as long as you can continuously renew it. If we
talk about every year, it
is 78% and the claim settlement ratio
of the company is 99.7% which is very good. Let
me tell you the difference between these two.
Incurred Claim Ratio is the amount that the company paid out of the
premium it collected from the market.
Suppose, if the company collected Rs
100 crore in premium in one year, then the company paid Rs
78 crore out of it.  If 78% of it is
paid, then out of the total
claim that came to them, that much
percentage of claim is passed in the claim, so out of the total
claim that came to them,
99.7% of the claim is passed in the computer,
so the difference between the two will be this, the
claim settlement is an in-house claim, there is
no TPA, so the claim is passed easily, if we
talk about cashless network, then they have
6700 plus network in the whole of India, so
you will get their comfort easily at almost all places, if we
talk about the grace period, then
you will get a grace period of 30 days, according to them, if the
policy expires and for
some reason you are
not able to make the payment due to any financial problem, then
even after the policy expires, you have 30 days
time, pay the premium of the policy in 30 days,
then your policy will
continue, if we talk about the policy
type, then you
can take the policy in both individual or family floater mode, if you
want to take it individually, you can also take
family floater for the family  If you want, you
can take it now. There is no such thing. There is no
further payment,
so this is a good thing because
in other companies, after 60 or 65, a copayment of 20% starts after 65,
but there is no copayment here.
So let's move ahead and talk about the company's
plan. What all does the company
offer? First of all, let's talk about in-
patient care.
In infection care, the company will take care of you. There is
no limit on room rent. Be it a
single private room, a suite
room, or any category above that, there is
no limit there either. You can take any room. There will be
ICU charges, whatever
uptodate will be borne by the company. Here,
in free hospice, you will have to pay the company for 60 days.
Before you get admitted, you will have to pay the expenses of 60 days, whether it is
doctor's expenses or any medical
test, whatever expenses there are, the company will pay
you there.
After the charges are paid, the company will pay you for the expenses for 180 days. Let's
talk about decontamination treatment.  So here
all the DK treatments will be covered for you, there is no
such thing because you are not covered,
all the DKs are covered for you here and the
company will pay you here and there, if we
talk about domestic care
then the company is taking care of you here also,
if your treatment is
in such a condition that you cannot go to postpartum,
your treatment is going on at home,
if the doctor is treating you at home then the
company will pay you only there, let's talk
about organ donor, if suppose someone
donates an organ to you, if someone does any other act then
in that condition the company will bear the
expenses of both you and the other doctors who are doing it
and now it will pay you this, let's
talk about treatment,
in home treatment the company will pay you only 5%,
maximum 25000,
what is the difference, if here you are
not getting admitted due to some reason then the
doctor is treating you, but
what is the matter in home care, if you
want to do it at your home, then this comes under home care, the
company will pay you here  The
company pays a maximum of 5% only or ₹25000, whichever is less. Let's
talk about alternative treatment.
If you don't want to do allopathic treatment,
you want to do
Siddharth Yunan or Ayush treatment, then the
company always pays you everything.
For barrier surgery, the
company pays you 50%. If the
shot is worth 10 lakhs, then the company will pay you
₹500000. Battery service means
obesity surgery, that is,
whatever treatment you get in it, the
company pays you 50%. But the
minimum cost of makeup in it should be 10 lakhs.
If you are taking a policy of 5 lakhs, then the
company will not cover you there. Let's
talk about ambulance, the
company pays you van person van percentage here. The
maximum amount that will come for you is
₹10000. So, the
company will pay you van percentage for the ambulance here. Let's talk
friends, your ambulance is also
covered here. The company will cover you.  Now you understand and
do it here, but its cover is
completely separate, meaning your
cover will not be of any use to it.
If you take 500000 rupees and you do an ambulance or air ambulance,
then your base subscription will be ₹5
lakh, the cover of this ambulance will
remain yours. Similarly, if you take 10
lakh rupees, then your subvention will be 10 lakh
rupees, this ambulance will stop doing it.
If you do an air ambulance, then
I think none of your money will be detected. The
separate cover for air ambulance which the
company has given you is
exactly equal to the base cover. The
company will detect it from there. Let's talk about
worldwide cover, then the company
also gives you worldwide cover here.
If you want, you want to get treatment outside India, then you
can do it there too, but
your minimum cover should be 25 lakhs.
If you take 2500000 rupees, then only
that company gives you this feature. If
your cover is less than that, then the company does not give you this feature. Let's
talk.  If we talk about modern treatment,
then your modern treatment, robotic
surgery is also a part of it, that is also
covered in it. Let's talk about bonus,
so friends, here in the year in which you do
not take a claim, then the company
gives you a bonus of 20% every year, which is a
guaranteed bonus, it will
increase once, but if you take a claim later, then
it does not decrease. Yes, whatever
policy you take, the year you make a claim,
you will not get the bonus the next year,
but the bonus you have already received will
never decrease, that means
you will get this bonus, it will be guaranteed. Let's
talk about restoration,
friends, if your insurance gets exhausted, then the
company restores your UPTO 100%, which is
your shot, and for the same
person and the same illness also the company
gives you restoration here, for example,
your Rs. 500000 is running, if
you get admitted for any disease, if it gets
exhausted and now you get
admitted for the same disease again, then
you will get Rs. 25 again.  You can pay a full Rs. 1 lakh
if ​​the company restores you and gives it to you. Let's move
ahead and talk about help checkup.
Friends, here the company gives you help
checkup and
half percent of whatever you have. If your Subhash is worth Rs. 10 lakh,
then the company pays you Rs. 5000.
If your Samosa is worth Rs. 5 lakh, then the
company pays you Rs. 2500 for help checkup
but there should be a limit of
maximum Rs. 10,000. If your shot is worth Rs. 25 lakh
or Rs. 50 lakh, then also the company pays
you a maximum of Rs. 10,000 only. Let's
talk about medical checkup. For hospital Delhi cash,
if you are admitted in the hospital for more than 10 days,
then the company gives you a feature
of hospital daily cash, so the company gives
you Rs. 20,000 for long term there, for
10 days or more. If you
keep meeting later, then let's talk about second
medical tally consultation and digestion and
nutrition assistant.
If you want to get a critical
opinion and
you are not happy with the service you are getting in your hospital, that is,
if you
can get any treatment and here you can access it through
this mobile application, then
you can talk there. Similarly,
for telemedicine and nutrition, you can talk there
that the company here will give you the documents within 60 minutes,
that is, the hospital prepares all your
documents and sends them to the company, so
within 60 minutes the company gives you your pre-book.
Now let's talk about this, the company
also gives you some add-on covers here.
If you want, you can increase the features of your policy by adding add-on covers.
First of all, let's talk about maternity, for
this you can take people, so the
company pays you up to 10% here,
maximum ₹10 lakh. Yes friends, if your
salary is ₹10 lakh and the company is
paying you 10%, that means the company pays you ₹1 lakh
for the material. Similarly,
take your  If it is Rs 1 crore, then the company
here gives you a maximum of ₹10 lakh. Here the
deal is, so you can also activate it by adding an add-on cover. Let's
talk about the new born baby cover, so
here you can add the new born baby cover,
so the company provides
you double cover of the cover here for the new born,
if their newborn baby faces
any problem, then the company covers
you because the company pays you double of the cover which is Metallica,
here you get double
cover
vaccination for new born baby, new born baby
is covered
1% off but the maximum limit should
be 10000, maximum 10000 here the
company covers you, let's talk about the
category, then the company here you
can take a cover for critical,
if any critical happens to you, then the
lump sum is paid there, equal to
if you have an insurance of 10 lakh rupees and
any critical is detected to you,
then the company will give you equal to  Base
insurance means 10 lakh rupees separately, the
company pays you lump sum, so 10 lakh rupees for treatment is
separate, the company is paying
you 10 lakh rupees equal to the short insurance
there, let's
talk about personal accident, then
personal accident is paid
there, so for that also you
can take base cover, so if there is
any problem due to any accident, then the
company is paying for that too, let's talk about
clamp protector, friends, there are some non-
medical items in your policy which the
company does not cover, if you take claim allowance
here, then those non-medical
items are also covered by the company, many times
those non-medical items can also cost you up to 20-30-50 thousand,
so whenever you
take a policy, definitely add a claim protector to your policy,
friends, the last thing is that
whenever you take this insurance, after taking this,
whenever you remove the policy in the next year, then
whatever old insurance you have, the company will cover
your old insurance due to inflation.  It
increases the premium accordingly, so whenever you take the submission and
remove the policy, then whatever inflation will be
given to you according to the old one, then whatever
inflation has been there, as per
your understanding, it
protects the inflation and for this you
can take these bases, so friends let's talk
about the waiting period, when
you take the company's policy, then
how much does the company charge on waiting, so let's talk about the
initial waiting period, whenever you
take a new policy, the company will
put you on a waiting period of 30 days, only your
accident will be covered for 30 days, there will be
no news in it, after 30 days your policy will be
activated and almost all your
diseases will be covered, there are some diseases which
remain, whatever disease remains, it
comes under specific disease, that
disease will be covered for you, after 2 years there are such
diseases which gradually develop in your body,
like you have thyroid, diabetes, kidney failure,
liver
related disease, so these diseases which are
major diseases, they are covered only after 2 years, let's
talk about it  Yes Priya,
while taking the policy of existing disease, if you have any
disease and you have declared it and the
company has accepted your proposal,
then the company will cover it after 2 years. So, the
company which is pre-adjusting,
covers it after two years. Let's talk about
barrier surgery, here for surgical
surgery, the
waiting period is increasing to 3 years.
For critical surgery, your waiting period will be
60 to 90 days, it will depend on
different diseases and the
waiting period for maternity will be 9 months here.
So friends, whatever I have
told you till now, the company covers everything. Now let's
talk about what the company does not cover. So, first of all, if you are getting admitted
for
routine medical treatment, for any
routine medical examination, then the
company will not cover it.
You will have to bear the expenses yourself. The company will not
cover dental treatment.
Here, if the dental treatment is
due to an accident, then the company will  Let's talk about the
cost of spectacles, this too the company will
not cover. If there are any procedures related to birth control, then the
company will not cover that either. Apart from this, if there is
hormone replacement therapy, then the
company will not cover this either. Apart from that, the
company will not cover any rules and regulations related to
treatment for drugs and alcohol. If there is any
problem with alcohol or body, then the
company will not cover this either.
If you are taking directory supplements
without being prescribed by a doctor,
then the
company will not cover it. If any such
situation arises like if there is a
situation of nuclear weapon attack or chemical attack outside, then
this also the company will not cover. The
company will not cover any kind of OPD treatment in this policy. Along with this,
if you are doing any adventure sport,
any scope badhaaving or car racing, then the
company does not cover such adventure sports.
Apart from this, friends, if you
want to know something more about this plan,
want to get some more information, then you can
go to their website.  You
can get information about this by visiting www.iccilomba.com. Apart from this, if you have
taken out a policy and are facing any problem,
you need to make any changes in the policy
or you need to file a claim, then you
can do so by calling their customer care number (double zero to triple zero).
Apart from this, you can also email the company
customer support icici lombard.com.
Here you can also email if you
want to make any changes in your policy or
if you want to file a clear claim,
then you can do it here. So
friends, this was our video today.
Do let us know how you liked our video. If you have any
questions, you
can ask us in the comments section. If you
want to give any feedback, you can also do so.
Apart from this, if you liked our video,
then subscribe to our channel,
like our video.
And if you find this
video helpful, then
you can share it with your friends. Thank you.